## Ashutosh Singh, AI Engineer

Rostock, Germany, +4917670784103, ashutosh.singh.de@gmail.com

LINKS <u>LinkedIn, Github, Stackoverflow, Portfolio</u>

PROFILE I have 3+ years of experience working with NLP startups in India. I am currently doing applied research at

Fraunhofer Institute with tasks such as Image Segmentation and Multi-Modal Signal Processing, Keypoint Detection etc. using Deep Learning, trying to apply these technologies to industry projects.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Dec 2022 - Present Research Associate(Wissenschaftlicher), Fraunhofer IGD

Rostock

Biomass Measurement: Fish measurement pipeline combining keypoint detection, inverse relative depth estimation and relative to absolute depth regression.

Nov 2021 - Nov 2022 **Research Assistant, Fraunhofer IIS** 

Erlangen

Studying and analyzing latest developments in efficient architectures of Image Segmentation. Developed U-Net like architectures based on more efficient and sparse architectures like Depth-Wise separable and grouped convolutions.

Master Thesis - Multimodal Signal Processing and Data Fusion methods for emotion detection on datasets like MAHNOB-HCI using end-to-end Deep Learning.

Pytorch for running the experiments and Weights and Biases for experiment tracking.

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021 Machine Learning Engineer, Jio Haptik Tech Ltd

Mumbai

Co-Developed modules for Intelligent Virtual Assistant development platform. Focus was more on NER and Small-talk components. We used BERT + CRFs for sequence classification.

Worked on the Diagnostics module to improve the quality of data being used to train the virtual assistants.

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018 Data Scientist, jubi.ai

Mumbai

Utilized various ML and DL based methods to develop components such as Intent Detection(Text Classification) and Entity Recognition(Sequence Labeling) for Intelligent Virtual Assistants.

Deployed the systems using python based web frameworks, Docker and AWS Elastic Container Services

**EDUCATION** 

Nov 2020 - Nov 2022 **Master of Science, Computational Engineering** 

Erlangen

Multidisciplinary masters course with focus on Mathematics, Computer Science and Digital Signal Processing.

Brief list of subjects Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Machine Learning in Signal Processing, Image and Video

Compression, , Image and Video Multidimensional Signal Processing, Linear Algebra, Optimization for Engineers.

Nov 2020 - Nov 2022 **Master of Science, Computational Engineering** 

Università della Svizzera

Lugano

Sultanpur

Brief list of subjects during a semester at USI - High Performance Computing, Intro To Bayesian Computing, Advanced Topics in Machine Learning

Friedrich-Alexander Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics Engineering Kamla Nehru Institute of Technology

Graduated with honors

June 2013 - June 2017

SKILLS	Computer Vision	Deep Learning	Natural Language Processing
	Python	Machine Learning	Web Development
Tools	Github	Mlflow/Weights & Biases	CV Annotation Tools
	Pytorch	Amazon Web Services	Django
	Docker	MongoDB	HuggingFace Environment
	Numpy	Pandas	Langchain/LLMs

LANGUAGES English C1

Hindi Native Speaker